Guide to the Nathaniel Gage Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH 1992-048
  - Rosenshine, Barak #2, 1970 Oct 1-1976 Dec 16 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rosenshine, Barak (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ross, S. E. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - SCRDT: Roy, Larnders (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Rubin, Louis (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Notes, card
  - Rudin, Stanley (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - SCRDT: Shaftel, Fannie IIA (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Memos
  - Skinner, B. F. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Reprint
  - Sharan, Shlomo (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Simon, Anita (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sparks, Lois Remmers (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, paper, c.v.
  - SCRDT: Spellman, Judy (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, dissertation abstract, recommendation, c.v.
  - Spindler, George D. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stanley, Dr. Julian (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stiles, L. J. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stolurow, Lawrence M. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stukat, K. G. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - [Miscellaneous] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Northern California Association (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Directory, newsletters
  - Phi Delta Kappa (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, paper, article, newsletter
  - Ramirez, Arnulfo (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Ravenswood (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Project proposals, articles, memo
  - Regents Ed. Psy. Exam (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, review
  - Rimland, Bernard (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Skinner, B. F. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, newsletter clippings
  - Sparks, Gigi Mohlman (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Spencer Foundation (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, newsletter, brochures
  - Spencer Foundation: Gage, Hedges, & Olkin Proposal & Correspondence. Proposal (1st prop.), 1978 Oct-1979 Sep (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Correpondence, proposal
  - SUNY Albany Ed. Psych. Grades (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Correspondence, grades, exam
  - SUNY Albany, Ed. Psych 740: Seminar in Research on Teaching (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Notes, syllabi, exams, class list
  - SUNY Albany, Ed. Psych. 502: Chapter Outlines (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Notes
  - SUNY Albany, Education Newsletter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Newsletters, notes
  - SUNY Albany, Ed. Psych. 502: Midterm 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Notes, exams
  - SUNY Albany, Ed. Psych. 502: Midterm 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Exams
  - S. U.: C-AAA (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Draft of 1986/87 Annual Report
  - Switzerland Book (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Switzerland (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, abstracts, papers, notes
  - Taiwan (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, papers, booklet
  - Tate: USSR Pedagogical Research (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Reprints, booklet
  - Teachers College Press (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, contract, author's questionaire, style sheet
  - Teachers College Record (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, notes, newsletter
  - Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, notes, reviewer materials
  - Tomic, Welco (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, paper
  - University of Washington (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Vanderbilt University (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, articles, notes, fliers
  - van der Syde, Peter (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Waxman-Walberg Book (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Wong, David (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Letters of recommendation, correspondence, c.v.
  - Wong, David (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, papers, proposals, reading lists
  - Woolfolk, Anita (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, reprints, article, paper
  - Yee, A. H. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, papers, articles
  - Yee, Albert H. (II) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, papers, articles, book proposal
  - Yee, Albert H. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, papers, articles, letter of recommendation
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1994-163
  Additional papers consisting of correspondence, articles, lectures, memorial resolutions, minutes, obituaries, clippings, programs, and brochures.
  - Achtenhagen, Frank, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baxter, Juliet A., 1988-82 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bush, Robert N. [Memorial Resolution], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Educational Research Association, 1993-94 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foat, Classie, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Francisco, Norma, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Freiberg, H. Jerome, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Garza, Maria Teresa, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guba, Egon G., 1986, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Handbook of Educational Psychology, 1988-89 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hess, Robert, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hess, Robert, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hess, Robert, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hess, Robert [Memorial Resolution], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Morsh, Joseph E. [reprints], 1954-56 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mitman, Alexis, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mitzel, Harold [reprint], 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Society for the Study of Education, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - San Francisco State University; Gage's talk on "Art, Science, and Teaching from the Standpoint of an Eclectic Purist", 1991-92 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spain; two lectures by Gage in Madrid, 1992 Fall (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs
  - SUNY Albany; Gage held visiting professor appointment, 1988 Fall (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SUNY Albany, Graduate Research Initiative: Teacher Effectiveness, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stringfield, Samuel, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tanner, Laurel, 1987-90 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - TATE (Teaching and Teacher Education), 1988-90 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - TATE (Teaching and Teacher Education), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - TATE (Teaching and Teacher Education), 1992-94 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Texas A&M, 1991-92 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Tisher, Richard (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Tyler, Ralph W., 1990-94 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wong, Lily, 1987-93 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Wong, Lily, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wragg, E.C. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Yates, Gregory C.R., 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Yee, Albert H., 1998-94 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes photograph
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1995-165
  - Aera 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aera 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aera 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Teachers [1 of 4] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Teachers [2 of 4] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Federation of Teachers [3 of 4] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Teachers [4 of 4] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Banks, Henry (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beckum, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cal State University (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cape of Good Hope Foundation (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chall, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cooney, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Crawford, Como, Stayrook (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cremin, Larry (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Educational Researcher [1 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Educational Researcher [2 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Educational Researcher [3 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Educational Researcher [4 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Feldhusen, John (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Murdoch University (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Purdue University [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Purdue University [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Some Reflections On Research (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stanley, Julian e. [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanley, Julian e. [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stevens, Ellen (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Teacher Assessment (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Teachers College (Press) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - University of Illinois 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - USAID (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Wittrock, M.e. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1998-019
  - AERA (American Educational Research Association) 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AERA 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AERA 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - APA (American Psychological Association) meeting 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - APA meeting 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - APA 1996, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - APA 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - APA meeting 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - APA 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - APA 1994-95 and Divs. 15, 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - APA meeting 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AERA 1996 Distinguished Contributors Awards Committee (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AERA 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bennett Reviews (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Case, Robbie (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clift, Renee (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carnoy, Martin (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cronin, Dennis (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cuban, Larry (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Corno, L. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gall, Mark D. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gallimore, Richard (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gottesman, Irving (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gudmundsdottir, Sigrun (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hess, Robert (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hungary 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - ISATT (Int. Study Assoc. on Teacher Thinking) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Inkeles, Alex (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jackson, Philip W. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jaegar, Richard M. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Journal of Educational Psychology (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Krathwohl, David R. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Krumboltz, John (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - George, Alex and Julie (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SkillsBank (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Houghton, Mifflin (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Houghton, Mifflin (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Houghton, Mifflin 1994; interviews by Robin Bird (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Houghton, Mifflin (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Houghton, Mifflin 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Houghton, Mifflin 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Metcalf, Kim (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National Academy of Education (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Needels, M. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Postlewaite, T. N. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Review of Educational Research (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rosenshine, E. V. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Schrag, Francis (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Skeff, Kelley (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - S. .U. 1-CFA-008, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanley, Julian (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - S. U. 1-CFA-008, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bartosik Stocking, Vicki (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stone, George C. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stones, Edgar (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SUSE 1-CFA-008 Jan. 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - SUSE 1-CHA-037 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stringfield, Sam (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Taiwan 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Thorndike, E. L. and James, William (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Tom, A. Teaching as a moral craft. Reviews of (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tyack, David. Teacher Behavior (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Winne, P. H. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Wittmann, Werner (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Wong, David (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-069
  - Agency for International Development, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Lorin, 1991-93 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CASBS, 1965, 1985-98 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Crawford, John, 1987-99 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dunkin, M. J., (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dunkin, M. J., (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dunkin, M. J., (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dunkin, M. J., (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Snow, Richard Eric, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2003-048
  - AERA 2000 Appts. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AERA 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AERA 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AERA Program 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AERA 2000 New Orleans (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AERA 2000 Divisions (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AERA 2000 Registration & Hotel (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AERA 2000 Invisible College (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AP A (American Psychological Association) 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Animal Teaching (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Attention Deficit Disorder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Berliner, David C., correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Berliner, Visit to, of Gage's Nov. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Berliner, Brett (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Berliner: NA Ed. Nomination (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Berliner: Publications, 1977-98 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Berliner, David c., correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Berliner, David C., correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Burstall, Clare, correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cardelle-Elwar, Maria, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cholesterol Studies (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Christopher M., correspondence, 1987-2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Camo, Lyn, correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Crawford, John, correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Crawford, John, correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Crawford, Handbook Ch., 2nd Version (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Crawford, John, Papers 2/89 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Coladarci, Ted, correspondence, 1992-97 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Crawford Book (1 of2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Crawford Book (2 of 2) I (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cronbach, Lee 1., correspondence, 1979-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Flanders, Ned & Mary, correspondence, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Freiberg, H. Jerome, correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Publications, Accession ARCH-2004-303
  - Vol. 1, Nos. 1-20, 1940-49 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 2, Nos. 21-33, 1949-53 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 3, Nos. 35-47, 1953-68 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 4, Nos. 50-60, 1959-63 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 5, Nos. 60a-67, 1962-65 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 6, Nos. 68-79, 1964-67 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 7, Nos. 81-93, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 8, Nos. 96-141, 1969-85 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 9, Nos. 142-161, 1989-98 (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2005-136
  - Publications; biographical and bibliographic information; trip to Belgium (2001) (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2010-003
  - Drafts of his manuscript A Theory of Teaching, 2002-2004 and undated (Box 1)
  - Drafts of chapters for A Theory of Teaching, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - Draft of and files pertaining to "Essence and Accident in Process-Product (Box 1)
  - Research on Teaching," by Gage and Margaret C. Needels, 1986-89 (Box 1)
  - Unpublished papers byN. L. Gage, 1953-2001 [see attached listing for titles] (Box 2)
  - Unpublished and undated papers by N. L. Gage [see attached listing for titles] (Box 2)
  - List ofpublished and other writings ofN. L. Gage 1940-1999 (Box 2)
  - CV and biographical information ofN. L. Gage May 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Materials re A Theory of Teaching (drafts, notes, misc.) (Box 2)
  - Email and correspondence, 2002-07 (Box 2)
  - Email and correspondence, 2007-08 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980-83, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 2)